Today we are celebrating the day
امروز داریم روزی را جشن می‌گیریم
which is a very, very important issue, absolutely
که روز بسیار بسیار مهم، بدون شک
the most important, we can say, day, when
می‌شود گفت مهم‌ترین روزی است که
such a great happening took place.
در آن چنین اتفاق عظیمی رخ داد؛
And it had to take place that way
.و باید که به آن شکل اتفاق می‌افتاد
it was all in a way that strict.
.چون همه چیز به نوعی مقدر شده بود
In My last lectures I have told you
در سخنرانی‌های اخیرم، به شما گفته‌ام
how Christ was created first in the heavens.
.که مسيح چطور ابتدا در آسمان‌ها خلق شد
In the Devi Mahatmya, if you read that,
،در دوی ماهاتمیام، اگر آن را بخوانيد
He was created as Mahavishnu
او به صورت ماهاويشنو آفريده شد
and is mentioned very clearly, that first
و خيلی روشن اشاره شده است که
He was created as an egg.
.ابتدا او به صورت تخم خلق شد
It is written in this book,
،اين مطلب در اين کتاب
which perhaps was written about 14,000 years back.
.كه شايد حدود 14000 سال پيش نوشته شده، آورده شده است
It’s a book that predicts about Christ,
.اين کتابی است كه در مورد مسيح پيش‌گويی می‌کند
and that is why people in the West, specially,
و برای همین است که مردم به خصوص در غرب
offer an egg to each other as a friend.
.به عنوان یک دوست، به همديگر تخم‌مرغ هديه می‌دهند
The first  existence came on this Earth as an egg, that was Christ,
اولین موجودی که به شکل یک تخم‌ بر این زمین آمد، مسیح بود
and part of it was kept in that stage
و بخشی از آن، در آن حالت نگه ‌داشته شد
and the rest of it was used by the Holy Ghost,
،و بقيه آن توسط روح‌القدس
by Mahalakshmi, to create Christ out of it.
.توسط ماهالاكشمی استفاده شد تا مسيح را از آن خلق كند
In that ancient book He was called as Mahavishnu;
،در آن کتاب قدیمی، او را ماهاویشنو نامیدند
means the greater form of Vishnu.
یعنی شکل والاتر ویشنو؛
But actually Vishnu is the father
.ولی در واقع ويشنو پدر است
and He is the Son created by the Holy Ghost.
.مسیح پسری است که توسط روح‌القدس خلق شد
After my lecture I would like, if you have the book,
و بعد از سخنرانی‌ام، مایلم اگر کتاب را داريد
to read it out to them, the whole texts of how Christ was created.
برایشان بلند بخوانید، تمام آن متنی را که می‌گوید مسیح چطور خلق شد؛
And when He was created He cried for his Father,
،و وقتی آفریده شد، برای پدرش گریست
as He cried also on the cross once.
.همان‌طور که یک بار هم وقتی روی صلیب بود گریه کرد
And He cried for years.
و او سال‌ها گريه کرد
And then Christ  in Mahavishnu state was blessed by His Father
و بعد مسيح در حالت ماهاويشنو توسط پدرش مورد رحمت قرار گرفت؛
who said that Your position will be placed higher than Mine
كه به او گفت: مقام تو بالاتر از من قرار خواهد گرفت
and You will be the Adhara; means the “Support of the Universe.”
.و تو "آدْهارا" به معنی "پشتيبان عالم" خواهی بود
See, how from Mooladhara He becomes the Adhara.
.ببينيد چگونه از مولادهارا، او تبديل به آدهارا می‌شود
This was all done at the heavenly stage –
تمام اين‌ها در مرحله آسمانی، می‌شود گفت
Vaikuntha stage you can say.
.در مرحله "وايكونتْها" اتفاق افتاد
Then He was given birth by the Holy Ghost,
،بعد روح‌القدس او را به دنیا آورد
who was the mother of Christ on this Earth
کسی که مادر مسيح بر زمين بود؛
who was nobody else but was the incarnation of Mahalakshmi;
او کسی نبود جز اينکارنيشن ماهالاکشمی؛
means She was Radha. Ra-dha.
يعنی او رادْها بود. رادها؛
“Ra” means energy, “dha” means the one who sustains energy.
را يعنی انرژی و دْها يعنی کسی که .انرژی را برقرار ‌نگه می‌دارد
There are many aspects of Easter one has to understand,
،جنبه‌های زيادی در ایستر وجود دارد .كه انسان بايد آنها را درک کند
but the most of all is why did He die
اما مهم‌تر از همه این است که چرا مسیح رحلت ‌كرد؟
and why was He resurrected?
و چرا دوباره زنده شد؟
This point I have not yet touched, perhaps, so clearly.
.شاید تاکنون به این نکته خیلی به وضوح اشاره نکرده‌ باشم
That’s the point I want to tell you today.
.اين نكته‌ای است که امروز می‌خواهم در مورد آن با شما صحبت کنم
It’s only you people can understand the importance of the life of Christ.
فقط شما هستید که می‌توانید اهمیت زندگی مسیح را درک کنید؛
And when it is said that you have to get
و موقعی که گفته می‌شود
your realization through Christ,
،شما باید خودآگاهی‌تان را به واسطه مسیح بگیرید
it means that He had to pierce through the Agnya Chakra.
،یعنی او باید به چاکرای اگنیا نفوذ می‌کرد
He had to be there.
.باید که آنجا می‌بود
If He had not created this gap in the gate
،اگر او این فاصله را در دروازه ايجاد نکرده بود
we could never have got realization.
.هرگز نمی‌توانستيم خودآگاهی بگيريم
That is why it is said that you are to pass through
برای همین است که گفته می‌شود شما باید
the gates of heaven only with the grace of Christ.
.از دروازه‌های بهشت، تنها به لطف مسيح عبور کنيد
Of course that doesn’t mean churches, it doesn’t mean at all churches.
البته اين به معنی کليسا نيست، به هيچ وجه به معنی کليسا نيست؛
That you understand as Sahaja Yogis
،که شما به عنوان یک ساهاجايوگی می‌فهمید
that you have to pass through the Agnya Chakra, ultimately
.که بايد از چاکرای اگنیا عبور کنید
that’s the most difficult point where human beings have to pass.
در نهايت اين مشکل‌ترين نقطه‌ای است که .انسان بايد از آن بگذرد
Because, at the Agnya Chakra,
،چون در چاکرای اگنيا
your ego and superego are fully grown.
.ايگو و سوپرايگوی شما کاملا بزرگ شده‌اند
At the human stage only this ego is developed.
.در مرحله انسانی، تنها اين ايگو  بزرگ شده است
Now how to overcome the ego was a point.
،حال چگونگی غلبه بر ايگو مهم‌ترین نکته بود
And to overcome the ego, Christ had to do this.
و برای فائق آمدن بر ايگو، .مسيح ناچار بود اين کار را انجام دهد
When He was created in the beginning as Shri Ganesha –
در ابتدا او به شکل شری ‌گانشا خلق شد؛
you know the story how He was created – that the mala
،شما داستان چگونگی خلقت او را می‌دانيد
is the from the body of Parvati, the Holy Ghost,
اینکه مالا، از بدن پروتی، یعنی روح‌القدس
was taken out because before Her marriage
،بیرون آورده شد، چون او قبل از ازدواج
She was –
،باید برای حمام کردن
She had to cover Herself for Her bath with many scented things.
خودش را با چیزهای معطر بسیاری می‌پوشاند؛
And it was taken out, all these things
و همه این چیزها را بیرون آورد
and Her vibrations came out.
و ارتعاشات او خارج شد؛
And She created this child just to protect Her chastity;
،و این فرزند را فقط برای این خلق کرد تا از پاکدامنی‌اش حفاظت کند
outside Her bathroom She put him.
.خارج از حمام او را گذاشت
And you know the whole story about it.
،و شما کل داستان را در اين مورد می‌دانيد
Now there was a part of the element of the earth in that child.
،حال، بخشی از عنصر زمين در آن کودک وجود داشت
pruthivee-tattwa, was there.
پريتوی تاتوا وجود داشت.
All other centers –
،تمام مراکز
all other centers have got some elements in that.
تمام مراکز ديگر، بعضی از عناصر را در خود دارند؛
Some elements like pruthivee-tattwa is there, earth element;
.بعضی از عناصر؛ مثلا "پريتوي تاتوا" عنصر زمين است
then you have got water element, then you have got air element,
بعد عنصر آب را داريد، بعد عنصر هوا را داريد؛
and when you come to this it is the light element,
،و وقتي به اين می‌رسيد: اين عنصر نور است
it’s the light.
.اين نور است
And at this point, at Agnya Chakra,
،و در اين نقطه، در چاکرای اگنيا
He had to cross the last element, that was the light element.
،او مجبور بود از آخرين عنصر که نور بود عبور کند
That means He had to come out
،يعنی او باید به شکل حقيقی تنها قدرت الهی
into the true form of only the Divine Power, the Omkara,
یعنی "اومكارا" در بیاید که می‌توانيد آن را
the vibrations you can call it; or the absolute…
...ارتعاشات بنامید يا مطلق
you call it logos or something like that? The first sound, Brahma.
شما به آن عقل کل يا چنین چیزی می‌گویید؟ اولين صدا یا براهما؛
So He had to become the principle of Brahma.
.بنابراين او باید که به اصل براهما تبدیل می‌شد
To become the principle of Brahma, He had to get rid of
برای تبدیل شدن به اصل براهما، او باید از تمام عناصر دیگری
all other elements within Him.
.که در او بودند خلاص می‌شد
So the last was also the light element,
.پس آخرين عنصر هم عنصر نور بود
which He had to cross through.
،که بايد از آن عبور می‌كرد
So He had earth element in Him, as He was of the mala
،پس او عنصر زمین را در خود داشت؛ چون او از مالا بود
and all other elements within Him. But when it comes to the Agnya,
،و تمامی عناصر دیگر را .اما وقتی نوبت به اگنیا می‌رسد
He had to give up all the elements, that He had to die
او باید تمامی عناصر دیگر را رها کند ،برای همین باید که جسمش را ترک می‌کرد
the death of all these elements that were within Him,
مرگ تمامی عناصر درونش؛ تا به روح کامل
to become complete, absolutely pure, Spirit.
و مطلقا پاک تبدیل شود
What He did on subtle form works out on the gross form
کاری که او بر شکل ظریف انجام داد، بر شکل مادی نتیجه داد؛
and to do that He had to die.
و برای انجام آن کار باید جسمش را ترک می‌کرد
And whatever died in Him,
و آنچه در او مُرد
was that little element of earth element and other elements,
همان مقدار کم عنصر، از عنصر زمین و بقیه عناصر بود
and what came out of Him was pure Spirit.
.آنچه که از او بیرون آمد، روح پاک بود
[UNCLEAR]
.بله بیایید جلو
Was pure Spirit that was resurrected; the pure Spirit,
.روح پاک بود. آن بود که دوباره زنده شد؛ روح پاک
the pure Brahma-Tattwa which had formed the body of Christ,
،براهما تاتوای پاک که بدن مسیح را تشکیل داد
which was the body of Christ.
که بدن مسیح بود؛
And this happening came –
و این رخداد به وقوع پیوست؛
Christ has done what was predicted about Him –
.مسیح کاری را که برای او پیش‌گویی کرده بودند انجام داد
that He’s a savior, because He passed through that gate
که او یک منجی است؛ چون او از آن دروازه عبور کرد
to take people from this bodily existence,
تا مردم را از این وجود جسمی یعنی وجودی که
means the one that depends on the elements,
به عناصر وابسته است
to that existence which is Spirit.
.به وجودی که روح است ببرد
So the resurrection is where you become,
بنابراين رستاخير آنجایی است
from your attention, you jump into the attention of the Spirit.
که شما از توجه خود به داخل توجه روحتان پرش کنید؛
When you feel your attention, when you become the Spirit,
،.وقتی که توجه خودتان را احساس کنید وقتی که به روح تبدیل شوید
that is the happening which has happened to you also.
.آن اتفاقی است كه برای شما نيز افتاده است
But He became pure Spirit, pure Brahma Tattwa
ولی او به روح خالص تبدیل شد، به براهما تاتوای خالص؛
when He was resurrected,
،وقتی که دوباره زنده شد
and the resurrection is a happening of the Divine Power
و رستاخيز رویدادی است که در آن قدرت الهی که
which came from Mooladhara Chakra as just earth element, [unclear]
،از چاکرای مولادهارا نشأت گرفته بود فقط به شکل عنصر زمین
started growing. It took its birth from there,
،شروع به رشد کرد. از آنجا تولد گرفت
came up to Agnya chakra. There Christ was created
تا چاکرای اگنیا بالا آمد، آنجا مسیح خلق شد
to pass through all the elements,
تا از تمامی عناصر عبور کند
ultimately to enter into the Sahasrara
و سرانجام به داخل سحسرارا وارد شود
to become a complete Brahma Tattwa.
.تا به براهما تاتوای کامل تبدیل شود
And this was a very difficult thing,
.و اين کار بسیار مشکلی بود
was very experimental.
بسيار تجربی بود؛
And the experiment was quite a dangerous one.
و تجربه‌ای که واقعا خطرناک بود؛
It could have failed also,
،می‌توانست شکست هم بخورد
because He had in Him that human element,
،چون او در خود، آن عنصر انسانی
the body element which suffered.
عنصر بدنی را که زجر می‌کشد داشت؛
And He suffered, because this body element suffers,
و زجر کشید، چون اين عنصر بدنی است که زجر می‌کشد؛
not the Spirit; Spirit does not suffer. The body element suffers.
.نه روح؛ روح زجر نمی‌کشد؛ عنصر بدن زجر می‌کشد
So He had to suffer that body element
پس او ناچار بود که با آن عنصر بدنی زجر بکشد
and to get over it, to get out of it,
و برای خلاص شدن از آن، خارج شدن از آن
and to get out of it He had to have a tremendous courage.
.و برای خارج شدن از آن باید شهامت فوق‌العاده‌ای می‌داشت
It was such a difficult operation.
اين عمل بسيار مشكلی بود؛
Without Him nobody could have achieved.
.اگر او نبود، هيچ‌کس موفق نمی‌شد
He knew it was predestined,
او می‌دانست که اين کار از پیش مقدر شده بود؛
but it was one of the most difficult things to happen.
.ولی يكی از سخت‌‌ترين وقایعی بود که باید اتفاق می‌افتاد
I wonder how many Christians know the significance of an egg.
.نمی‌دانم که چند نفر از مسيحيان معنی تخم‌مرغ را می‌دانند
Now egg signifies a stage where you are before realization,
تخم‌مرغ بيانگر مرحله‌ای است كه شما .قبل از گرفتن خودآگاهی در آن هستيد
when you are in your egg shell;
،وقتی شما در پوسته تخمتان هستيد
that you are Mr. X; you are Mrs. Y; all that.
که شما آقای ایکس هستید، شما خانم ایگرگ هستید.
But when you mature fully inside the bird is ready
اما وقتی به طور کامل از درون رشد کنید، پرنده آماده است؛
and that is the time you are hatched.
و اين زمانی است كه شما از تخم بیرون می‌آیید
This is the time you get twice born.
.اين زمانی است که به تولد دوباره می‌رسید
So, actually the resurrection of Christ signifies that
پس در حقیقت رستاخيز مسيح نشان از آن دارد
and that’s why we give that egg to people saying,
و برای همین است که ما به مردم تخم‌مرغ می‌دهیم؛
“You are an egg,” a reminder of that,
یعنی شما یک تخم‌ هستید؛ برای به یادآوردن آن؛
“and this egg can become the spirit.”
.و اين تخم می‌تواند به روح تبديل شود
And also it is written that it was an egg when He came.
و نیز نوشته شده که وقتی او آمد یک تخم‌ بود؛
First He was created as an egg. Half of it remained
اول او به شکل یک تخم آفریده شد؛  نصف آن به شکل
as Shri Ganesha and half of it became Mahavishnu.
.شری‌گانشا باقی ‌ماند و نصف آن ماهاویشنو شد
Then He came on this earth
بعد او روی این زمين آمد
and He departed with all His elements
و با تمامی عناصرش رحلت کرد
and the pure vibrations formed His body,
.و ارتعاشات خالص، بدن او را تشکیل داد
and He remained there within all of you to be awakened,
و او آنجا ماند، درون همه شما، تا بیدار شود
and when the Kundalini takes your attention through that point,
،وقتی کندالینی توجه شما را از آن نقطه به آنجا ببرد
there you also become the Spirit.
.شما هم به روح تبدیل می‌شوید
That’s why He said, that “I am the gate, I am the door.”
برای همین گفت: من دروازه هستم، من در هستم.
He didn’t say, “I’m the destination.” He said, “I’m the door,”
.نگفت من مقصد هستم. گفت من در هستم
because you cannot become Christ.
.چون شما نمی‌توانید مسیح شوید
That’s why he didn’t say, “I’m the destination,”
برای همین نگفت من مقصد هستم
that you have to achieve Him,
كه ناچار باشید به او برسید؛
but He has created this space for you.
.بلکه او این فضا را برای شما خلق کرد
You can become spiritually awakened;
،شما می‌توانید به شکل روحانی بیدار شوید
you can become your Spirit. But Christ is an incarnation,
شما می‌توانید به روح خودتان مبدل شوید؛ .ولی مسیح یک اینکارنیشن است
He was the Son of God. And so He’s an incarnation,
او پسر خدا بود، پس او يک اينکارنيشن است؛
and that incarnation came on this earth
و آن اينکارنيشن فقط برای این روی زمين آمد
just to pull you out of your elements,
،که شما را از عناصر‌تان خارج كند
to make you become the Spirit.
.تا شما را وادار کند که به روح تبديل شويد
Now how is it that it was the most difficult thing?
حالا چطور است كه اين سخت‌ترين چيز بود؟
Because human beings had created in their heads
،چون انسان‌ها در فکرشان
all kinds of artificial barriers; you see whatever we think
.انواع موانع مصنوعی را به وجود آورده‌اند می‌بينيد به هرچه فکر می‌کنيم
and whatever we do with our mind is all dead,
،و هر کاری که با ذهن خود انجام می‌دهيم، تماما مرده هستند
is man made, is artificial,
ساخت بشر هستند، مصنوعی هستند؛
Because reality’s beyond your mind;
،چون حقیقت ورای ذهن شماست
it is not in your mind. You cannot conceive it; you cannot hold it.
،درون ذهن شما نیست. شما نمی‌توانید آن را بفهمید .شما نمی‌توانید آن را در ذهن نگه‌ دارید
Whatever is in your mind is not the reality, it is beyond.
..هر چه که در ذهن شماست واقعیت نیست .حقیقت ورای آن است
So, for a human being to accept something that is beyond mind
،پس برای یک انسان، پذیرفتن چیزی که ورای ذهن باشد
had become so difficult at the time of Christ because of Romans
در زمان مسیح بسیار مشکل شده بود؛ به خاطر رومی‌ها
and all these people coming up.
.و این افرادی که برخاسته بودند
And we are repeating the history again.
.و ما داريم تاريخ را دوباره تکرار می‌کنيم
They were so ego-oriented, they were so full of ego
آنها آنقدر ايگو محور بودند، آنقدر پر از ايگو بودند
that to destroy their ego
كه کسی باید برای نابود کردن ایگوی آنها،
somebody had to do this to create a passage.
.چنین کاری می‌کرد، تا گذرگاهی به وجود آورد
By His death so many things are proved,
با مرگ او چيزهای زیادی اثبات شد؛
that all those who crucified Him were stupid people,
که تمام کسانی که او را به صليب کشيدند، مردمی احمق بودند
they were ego-oriented, they were blind.
،آنها ايگو محور بودند، آنها کور بودند
They could not see what He was.
.آنها نمی‌توانستند ببينند او کیست
They could not see what a genuine personality He was.
.آنها نمی‌توانستند ببینند که او چه شخصیت شریفی است
They crucified Him.
،او را به صليب کشيدند
I mean it’s the greatest stupidity.
یعنی این احمقانه‌ترین کار است؛
And they crucified Him, it was all known because these people
و آنها او را به صلیب کشیدند. اين از قبل روشن بود؛
were so stupid that they would have only crucified him,
چون این افراد چنان احمق بودند که .فقط مصلوب کردن او از دستشان برمی‌آمد
what else they could do?
دیگر چه کاری می‌توانستند انجام دهند؟
Because they couldn’t bear with their little egos,
چون آنها با ايگوهای کوچک خود نمی‌توانستند
somebody who is so simple, who is so genuine, who is so true.
کسی که چنين ساده، چنين شریف .و چنين به حق باشد را تحمل کنند
So they crucified Him
برای همین او را به صليب کشيدند
and that crucifixion came as a breakthrough for us.
.و آن مصلوب کردن برای ما موجب پیشرفت بزرگی شد
But message for us is the resurrection part.
.ولی پیامش برای ما بخش رستاخيز آن است
Message for us is the resurrection and not crucifixion.
.پیام برای ما رستاخیز است و نه مصلوب شدن
Crucifixion is not the message, because He’s done for us.
مصلوب شدن پیام نیست؛ چون او آن را برای ما انجام داده است؛
This is the point where Jews must understand.
.اين نکته‌ای است که يهوديان بايد آن را بفهمند
The other day I was reading – today only –
چند روز پيش داشتم؛ همین امروز داشتم
some discussion with the Archbishop of Canterbury took place.
مناظره‌ای که با اسقف اعظم کانتربری شده بود را می‌خواندم
And the fellow who was asking him was asking him questions
و شخصی که داشت از او سوال می‌‌پرسید، سوالاتش را طوری می‌پرسید
as if he was asking questions to God.
.که انگار دارد آنها را از خدا می‌پرسد
In a way he said so also that, “I would ask this question to God,
.به شکلی که این را هم گفت: من این سوال را از خدا هم دارم
that, ‘Why is it so many Jews were killed?’”
که چرا این‌قدر یهودی کشته شد؟
They asked for it.
.آنها خودشان خواستند
They wanted that they must suffer
آنها می‌خواستند که حتما زجر بکشند؛
because they wouldn’t give the credit of suffering to Christ.
.چون اعتباری برای زجر کشیدن مسیح قائل نبودند
They thought, "We all have to suffer." Ego. It's ego.
.فکر می‌کردند که ما همه باید زجر بکشیم .ايگو. اين ايگو است
"How dare anybody suffer for us? We must suffer separately."
چطور يک نفر به خاطر ما زجر بکشد؟! .ما باید جداگانه زجر بکشيم
They couldn't give that credit to Christ and all the
آنها نتوانستند اين اعتبار را برای مسيح قائل شوند
later thinking was that, "We must suffer."
.و همه افکار بعدی اين بود كه ما بايد زجر بکشيم
So, whatever you think comes into action on this gross level,
،خوب هر چه به آن فکر کنید .در این سطح مادی به عمل در می‌آید
so Mr. Hitler was born and he made them suffer.
پس آقای هیتلر متولد شد و آنها را وادار کرد که زجر بکشند؛
And the stupidity of human beings
،و حماقت بشر
is responsible for all the problems
باعث تمامی مشکلاتی است که
that are created on this earth.
.در این زمین به وجود آمده است
The other question was, "How the children get leukemia?"
سوال دیگر این بود: چطور بچه‌ها مبتلا به سرطان خون می‌شوند؟
He would ask God, "How children get it?"
سوالش از خدا بود؛ چطور بچه‌ها مبتلا می‌شوند؟
If the parents are so frantic and speedy, children have to get it.
،اگر والدين خيلی عصبانی و عجول باشند قطعا بچه‌ها مبتلا می‌شوند.
If you are not relaxed person when you are married
،اگر موقع ازدواج، فردی آرام نباشید
and when you are going to have a baby;
،و وقتی که می‌خواهید بچه‌دار شوید
you are thinking of divorces and all sorts of nonsense,
،اگر به فکر طلاق و هر کار احمقانه‌ای باشید
that franticness will work on the child.
.آن پریشان‌حالی بر بچه اثر می‌گذارد
Psychologically it is a left side problem and the child has to be
،از نظر روان‌شناسی این مشکل کانال چپ است و بچه به محض تولد
a patient of leukemia as soon as he's born.
.به ناچار مبتلا به سرطان خون می‌شود
That is what it is.
!همین و بس
So the problems are created by human beings
بنابراین مشکلات به دست انسان‌ها
because of their stupidity.
.و به خاطر حماقتشان به‌وجود می‌آید
There is no problem that God has created for you.
.هیچ مشکلی وجود ندارد که خداوند برای شما خلق کرده باشد
He's solved all your problems. All your problems He solves;
.او تمام مشکلات شما را حل کرده است .تمامی مشکلات شما را او حل می‌کند
you have seen in Sahaj Yoga
شما در ساهاجایوگا دیده‌اید که
how He solves your little, little problems even.
.او چطور مشکلات کوچک کوچک شما را حتی حل می‌کند
But we create problem for ourselves by our stupidity,
،ولی ما برای خودمان مشکل درست می‌کنیم؛ با حماقتمان
by our addiction to elements,
،با اعتیادی که به عناصر داریم
to material things,
،به اشیاء مادی
to material habits. Matter sits on our head.
به عادت‌های مادی. ماده روی سر ما سوار می‌شود؛
That is on the, we can say, on the level of the earth element.
.که می‌شود گفت در سطح عنصر زمین است
Then we have other problems like emotional attachments:
.بعد ما مشکلات ديگری داريم؛ مانند وابستگی‌های احساسی
"This is my daughter; this is my child; this my; this is mine;
.اين دختر من است، اين فرزند من است، اين مال من است، اين مال من است
I'm so attached to my child."
.من خيلی به فرزندم وابسته هستم
Then, "This is my country. This is your country."
.بعد اين کشور من است، اين کشور شما است
We create problem. This Falkland camp...
.ما مشکلات را به ‌وجود می‌آوريم اين کمپ فالکلند؛
this Falkland this thing is an artificial problem, you can see that.
،این ماجرای فالکلند، یک مشکل ساختگی‌ است .این را می‌توانید ببینید
I mean, when these people went there, these spaniards,
،یعنی وقتی این افراد به آنجا رفتند، این اسپانیایی‌ها
They all should been given back to Spain.
.همه باید به اسپانیا برگردانده می‌شدند
And all from Brasil should be given back to Portugal.
،و همه آنها که اهل برزیل بودند .باید به پرتغال برگردانده می‌شدند
What are they doing there? If this is the situation.
.آنجا چه می‌کردند؟ اگر وضع بدین منوال است
But they are all human beings.
.ولی آنها همه انسان هستند
What is this territory business?
این بازاری که برای قلمرو به ‌راه انداخته‌اند چیست؟
So let the human beings live happily wherever they are.
.بگذارید آدم‌ها هر کجا که هستند خوشبخت زندگی کنند
What are they going to get out of this territory?
از این قلمرو می‌خواهند چه به‌ دست آورند؟
God never created Argentina, Chile, England and all that,
.خدا هرگز آرژانتين، شيلی، انگلستان و اینها را به وجود نياورده است
He created one homogeneous structure,
او ساختاری یک‌دست را خلق کرد
and it is to look after each other. Like a heart is created,
،و می‌خواست که از هم مراقبت کنند؛ ،مثل قلبی که خلق می‌شود
a liver is created, a brain is created, a nose is created.
،کبدی که خلق می‌شود، مغزی که خلق می‌شود .دماغی که خلق می‌شود
If they start fighting, say this eye starts fighting this eye.
اگر آنها شروع به جنگیدن بکنند؛ ...مثلا اگر این چشم پای جنگ با آن چشم را بگذارد
We laugh, but we human beings do the same thing.
.می‌خندیم؛ ولی ما آدم‌ها همین کار را می‌کنیم
We are all the time doing like this.
.ما دائم داریم همین کار را می‌کنیم
This is the stupidity of human beings, which is creating problem.
.این حماقت نوع بشر است که مشکلات را ایجاد می‌کند
And when you become very stupid,
،و وقتی شما خیلی احمق شوید
somebody horrible takes advantage of that
یک آدم خیلی ناجور از آن سوء استفاده می‌کند
and comes on this earth just like Hitler,
و روی زمین می‌آید. درست مثل هیتلر؛
and he tries to put you right.
،و می‌خواهد موضوع را به شما بفهماند
You don't need all that. You need only wisdom
شما به اینها احتیاجی ندارید؛ شما فقط به خرد
and your realization.
.و به خودآگاهی‌تان نياز داريد
And that is what is done today that you have got realization.
.و همین کار امروز انجام می‌شود؛ که شما خودآگاهی گرفته‌ايد
So Easter for Sahaj Yogis all over the world,
،بنابراين ايستر برای ساهاجايوگی‌ها در تمام دنيا
is the most important happening
مهم‌ترين رویداد است؛
because if it had not happened it would not have been possible
،چون اگر این رویداد اتفاق نيفتاده بود
to give realization to people.
امکان خودآگاهی دادن به مردم وجود نداشت.
I think Gavin will read it out to you later on about
فكر كنم گاوين بعدا آنچه را که در مورد مسيح
what is written about Christ in Devi Mahatmya.
.در دوی ماهاتمیام نوشته شده است، برای شما بلند بخواند
This book was written about 14,000 years back by Markandeya.
اين كتاب حدود 14000 سال پيش .توسط مارکانديا نوشته شده است
So imagine 14,000 years back he knew, being a seer,
تصور کنيد 14000 سال پيش؛
just like Blake, what was going to happen
او که مانند بلیک یک پیشگو بود؛ می‌دانست که قرار است چه اتفاقی بیفتد؛
when Christ was to come.
.زمانی که قرار بود مسیح بیاید
But He was called as Mahavishnu.
.اما به مسيح ماهاويشنو می‌گفتند
He was not Vishnu, He was the son of Vishnu.
او ويشنو نبود. پسر ويشنو بود؛
And how many Christians understand this about Easter.
و چند نفر مسيحی اين را در مورد ايستر می‌دانند؟
They don't. They - It's -
.آنها نمی‌دانند
Christianity today is nothing but a mental activity that's all,
مسيحيت امروز چيزی جز يک عملکرد ذهني نیست، همین؛
which is dead; nonsense it is.
.که مرده است، مزخرفات محض است
Just like any other nonsensical religion,
،درست عین مذاهب مزخرف دیگر
it has become another foolish, stupid religion,
آن هم مذهب ابلهانه احمقانه دیگری شده است
which has no meaning. Unless and until you get your realization,
،که هیچ معنایی ندارد. تا وقتی خودآگاهی‌تان را نگیرید
unless and until you feel the vibrations,
،تا وقتی ارتعاشات را حس نکنید
unless and until you feel this Divine Surrounding Power,
،تا وقتی که قدرت الهی اطراف را احساس نکنید
how will you understand?
چطور درک خواهید کرد؟
Because that's the only thing that is truth;
،چون اين تنها چيزی است كه حقيقت است
that's the only thing that is reality,
تنها چيزی است که واقعيت است؛
and unless and until you achieve it, how will you know about Christ?
و تا به آن نرسيد چطور از مسيح بدانید؟
And fighting about Him; how can you fight?
و برای او بجنگید؟ چطور می‌توانید بجنگید؟
I can't understand really.
واقعا متوجه نمی‌شوم
To Me, it's stupidity gone to another extreme.
در نظر من این حماقتی است که .از سوی دیگر به افراط رفته است
By this thing, what you do actually,
با این کاری که می‌کنید، در واقع دارید
is to use all these great incarnations to kill each other.
،از این اینکارنیشن‌های بزرگ .برای کشتن همدیگر استفاده می‌کنید
Can you imagine? The things that came to elevate you,
،می‌‌توانید تصور کنید؟ کسانی که برای متعالی کردن شما آمدند
to make you into higher living are now used,
برای این آمدند که شما را برای زندگی بهتری آماده کنند
the same things, the names are used to kill each other,
حالا از همان افراد، از همان نام‌ها، برای کشتن
to bring down each other. At the most,
.و پایین کشیدن همدیگر استفاده می‌کنید
if you reach a point where you don't understand,
،نهایتا اگر شما به نقطه‌ای برسید که متوجه نشوید
then they start saying, "It's a mystery."
.می‌گویید: این یک راز است
What is the mystery, in Sahaj Yoga there's no mystery.
راز دیگر چیست؟ .در ساهاجايوگا هيچ رازی وجود ندارد
It's all just there.
.همه چیز کاملا منطقی است
To Me, human beings are a mystery.
.برای من نوع بشر معما است
I don't understand them. I can't understand.
.آنها را درک نمی‌کنم. نمی‌توانم درک کنم
The resurrection of Christ has to now be collective resurrection.
.رستاخیز مسیح حالا باید رستاخیز جمعی باشد
This is what is Maha Yoga. Has to be the collective resurrection
این همان ماهایوگا است. باید رستاخیز جمعی باشد
and for this collective resurrection,
،و برای این رستاخیز جمعی
first of all Sahaj Yogis must decide to be collective.
پیش از هر چیز، ساهاجایوگی‌ها .باید تصمیم بگیرند که جمعی باشند
Because through Kundalini awakening you cross,
چون با بیداری کندالینی، شما عبور می‌کنید؛
no doubt, you cross through,
.شکی نیست. شما عبور می‌کنید
but you enter an area of collectivity.
ولی به حوزه جمعی بودن وارد می‌شوید
And if you do not allow that collectivy to permeate into you,
،و اگر نگذارید که آن جمعی بودن به شما نفوذ کند
then you come down.
.تنزل خواهید کرد
Supposing you become a state beyond the element,
،فرض کنید که شما به مرتبه‌ای ورای عنصر تبدیل شوید
the state where you are a collective being;
.مرتبه‌ای که شما موجودی جمعی باشید
you're aware of the collective being;
،شما از جمع آگاه هستید
you're aware that you are a part and parcel of the whole;
.شما به این که جزء لاینفک کل هستید آگاهی دارید
you're aware that you have to help your nose and your eyes
شما آگاه هستید که باید به بینی خود و چشمان خود کمک کنید؛
because you are part and parcel of the whole.
.چرا که جزء لاینفک کل هستید
You reach that stage where you understand that,
شما به مرحله‌ای می‌رسید که خواهید فهمید
"I am as important as other cells are,
من به اندازه دیگر سلول‌ها اهمیت دارم
and other cells are to be helped by me
.و من باید به سلول‌های دیگر کمک کنم
and they have to sustain me, we are one."
.و آنها باید مرا پشتیبانی کنند. ما یکی هستیم
There should be complete concord.
.باید اتحادی کامل وجود داشته باشد
This awareness comes after realization
اين آگاهی بعد از خودآگاهی به دست می‌آيد؛
and if you do not understand that this awareness,
،و اگر شما نمی‌فهمید که این آگاهی
that this collective awareness
،این آگاهی جمعی
is the only way you can stay in that area.
،تنها راه ماندن در این حوزه است
Otherwise you get out.
.بروید بیرون
You start having your smaller wells and you just go down into them.
شما برای خودتان چاه‌های کوچک‌تری را .دست و پا می‌کنید و فورا به داخل آنها فرو می‌روید
The more you start to expand yourself, you rise higher
.هر چقدر بخواهید خودتان را نشان دهید، بالاتر می‌روید
and then you are again with your badhas or whatever it is.
.و بعد دوباره شما می‌مانید و موانع و بقیه چیزها
But if you think that, "I have to live for the whole.
،ولی اگر فکر کنید که من باید برای همه زندگی ‌کنم
I'm responsible for the whole.
،من مسئول همه هستم
I'm responsible for creating a nucleus of a cell,
من مسئول خلق هسته‌ای از یک سلول هستم
which is going to look after the whole,
که قرار است مراقب همه باشد؛
and if I fall down the rest also suffers.
.اگر پایین بیفتم، بقیه هم زجر خواهند کشید
I have no business to fall down
،من حق ندارم سقوط کنم
because I have been resurrected to this point.
چون تا این نقطه رستاخیز پیدا کرده‌ام؛
I have entered into the state of collectivity,
من به مرحله جمعی بودن وارد شده‌ام
where my being, which is the Spirit,
،که در آن، وجودم که روح است
is the collective being and I have to stay there,
.وجودی جمعی است؛ و باید آنجا بمانم
I have to be there; I cannot fall, it's not the way I can live."
.من باید آنجا بمانم، حق ندارم سقوط کنم .به این شکل نمی‌توانم زندگی کنم
But I have seen after realization also,
،اما ديده‌ام حتی بعد از خودآگاهی گرفتن نيز
people cannot get out of their shells. They still remain in the shell.
.مردم نمی‌توانند از پوسته‌شان بيرون بيايند .آنها همچنان در آن پوسته باقی می‌مانند
They cannot spread their wings and sing
.نمی‌توانند بال‌هايشان را باز کنند و آواز بخوانند
and get out of their shell and just fly. They cannot do it.
.از پوسته‌شان خارج شوند و فورا پرواز کنند
They still stick on to their small ways of life,
.نمی‌توانند اين کار را بکنند ،همچنان به شیوه‌های تنگ‌نظرانه زندگی خودشان چسبیده‌اند
in a smaller ways, in every way. In a holiday you go.
.به هر شیوه‌ای به تعطیلات که می‌روید
You want to have a separate holiday. Why?
می‌خواهید تعطیلات جدایی داشته باشید. چرا؟
This is the holiday time, holy-day as they say. Holy day.
Holiday، حالا وقت تعطیلات است؛ Holy Day به قولی
This is the holy-day. When you are with other Sahaja Yogis
،این روز، مقدس است. وقتی با ساهاجایوگی‌های دیگر باشید
you are really enjoying a holiday.
.واقعا از تعطیلات لذت خواهید برد
Where do you enjoy your holiday otherwise? Which is the other way?
پس کِی می‌خواهید از تعطیلات لذت ببرید؟ چه راه دیگری هست؟
To be with them is the real holiday.
.با آنها بودن، تعطیلات حقیقی است
And that is why one should understand
برای همین باید دانست که
that you should expand your collectivity.
.شما باید جمعی‌تر شوید
If you do not expand your collectivity you are just a waste.
اگر جمعی‌تر نشوید، کاملا به درد نخور هستید؛
You are a wasteful creation of Sahaj Yogis,
یک موجود بی‌مصرف بین ساهاجایوگی‌ها هستید؛
which I'm sorry to say, will go down.
.که متاسفانه باید بگویم تنزل خواهید کرد
Such people show also, in the beginning,
چنین افرادی در ابتدا این را نشان می‌دهند که
gradually they start getting better and better and better.
.به تدریج بهتر و بهتر و بهتر می‌شوند
And once you are there in full state
،وقتی که کاملا در این وضعیت باشید
you really enjoy each other's company
واقعا از همراهی با یکدیگر لذت خواهید برد؛
without having any fears about them,
،بدون این که از آنها ترسی داشته باشید
without having any possessiveness about them,
،بدون این که از آنها هیچ حسادتی احساس کنید
without having any kind of expectation,
،بدون آنکه هیچ انتظاری از آنها داشته باشید
but just enjoying each other.
.تنها از همدیگر لذت می‌برید
That has to happen. Lies... All our cells in our body are like that.
.این اتفاقی است که باید بیفتد .مثل تمامی سلول‌های بدن ما که اینگونه هستند
If they can do it, why not we?
اگر آنها می‌توانند چنین کنند، ما چرا نتوانیم؟
Because we have so much of sense;
چون ما درایت بالایی داریم؛
at least we think we have more sense than the cells have.
.حداقل فکر می‌کنیم که ما بیشتر از دیگر سلول‌ها عقل داریم
At least it is expected, because we have evolved so much
حداقل چنین انتظاری می‌رود؛ چون ما از مرحله تک سلولی
from unicell to this state.
.تا به این مرحله، تکامل بسیار زیادی را پشت سر گذاشته‌ایم
And then you are the epitome of God's creation;
.بعد شما غایت خلقت خداوند هستید
you are the topmost people. Then why not?
شما بالاترین مردم هستید. پس چرا که نه؟
When you are resurrected the first thing that should happen to you
،وقتی دوباره متولد شده‌اید اولین چیزی که برای شما باید اتفاق بیفتد
is to understand that you are no more an individual,
،این است که باید بفهمید دیگر یک فرد نیستید
but you are a collective being. You are no more an individual.
.بلکه شما یک موجود جمعی هستید. دیگر یک فرد نیستید
All things which make you circumcise your individuality -
تمام مواردی که باعث می‌شوند فردگرایی شما جان تازه‌ای به خود بگیرد را
throw that away.
دور بریزید
You're no more an individual. All problems which come to you
شما دیگر یک فرد نیستید. تمامی مشکلاتی که به شکل مشکلات فردی
as individual problems are absolutely useless, false, wasteful.
،به سوی شما می‌آید، تماما به‌ درد نخور دروغین و بی‌ارزش هستند
Think of the collective problems. I enjoy such people.
.به فکر مشکلات جمع باشید .من از این گونه افراد خوشم می‌آید
Like the other day Fergie was anxious to know about Bristol -
،مثل چند روز پیش  که فرگی مشتاق بود بداند در بریستول
which points are there,
کدام نقاط از مادر زمین هستند
which are giving vibrations from the Mother Earth.
.که ارتعاشات می‌دهند
He's worried about the whole of Bristol - all the Jamaicans,
،او نگران کل بریستول بود، نگران همه جامائیکی‌ها
then about the whole British people,
بعد نگران کل مردم انگلیس؛
and then of the whole world you should be.
.بعد باید نگران کل دنیا باشید
That's what one should think. One should not think,
فقط آن یک نفر نباید نگران باشد.
"How will my daughter get married?
نباید به این فکر بود که دخترم چطور ازدواج خواهد کرد؟
How can I get a ticket to go there?"
چطور برای رفتن به آنجا بلیط بگیرم؟
All these nonsensical ideas should be given up
باید همه این افکار بیخود را کنار گذاشت؛
because you are now entered into the Kingdom of God
.چون شما الان به قلمرو خداوند وارد شده‌اید
and He's going to look after you.
خداوند می‌خواهد که از شما مراقبت کند؛
Because that state you establish within yourself
چون آن حالت را در خودتان تثبیت می‌کنید
that you are a collective being.
که موجودی جمعی هستید
All other things will drop out.
،بقیه مسائل به حال خود رها می‌شوند
Gradually everybody will be molded.
.به تدریج همه تغییر وضعیت می‌دهند
Even the most difficult I have seen, have improved.
.حتی سخت‌ترین افراد؛ این را دیده‌ام که پیشرفت کرده‌اند
But what about you, the one who is improving everybody else,
،ولی شما چه؟ یک نفر که دارد پیشرفت می‌کند .هر کس دیگری
what about you? How far you are there?
شما چطور؟ تا کجا پیش رفته‌اید؟
How far in your faith that you know that,
تا چه حد ایمان دارید که بدانید
"I have entered into the Kingdom of God
من وارد قلمرو خداوند شده‌ام
and that every action mine is looked after and guided by His power
و هر عملی از من مورد حفاظت و راهنمایی قدرت اوست
and I'm aware of it.
و من از آن آگاهم؛
I'm aware that I have entered into the Kingdom of God
من آگاه هستم که وارد قلمرو خداوند شده‌ام
which is expressed through my collectivity."
.قلمرویی که با جمعی ‌بودن من متجلی می‌شود
So collectivity is the nature of a Sahaj Yogi.
.بنابراین جمعی بودن، ذات یک ساهاجایوگی است
And that's what one has to realize.
.و این چیزی است که انسان باید بفهمد
May God bless you.
.رحمت خداوند شامل حال شما باشد
Is it all right now? Just time.
.درست است حالا؟ سر ساعت
How I manage, without looking at the watch?
.چطور مدیریت کردم؟ بدون نگاه کردن به ساعت